ABIDAN MARTINEZ

React Developer

Certified Computer Science and Programming individual with handson experience in front and back-end coding. Capable of adding new features, fixing bugs, and revamping an existing website. Ability to collaborate & grab business expectations focusing on creating outstanding value and satisfactory client experience.

CONTACTS



Fresno, CA 93703 210-649-0761



abidanmtz@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/abidanmartinez github.com/abidanm1000 portfolio

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE

Frontend Mastery Clever Programmer Bootcamp Dec 2021 – April 2022

BACHELOR'S DEGREE

Information Technology Fresno Pacific University Jan 2020 – May 2021

ASSOCIATE DEGREE

Information Technology Fresno City College Aug 2017 - May 2020

SKILLS

Technologies:

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScr

JavaScript ES6+

Python

Markdown

jQuery

React.js

Bootstrap

Django

Firebase

Moralis

REST API

Git

UX/UI

Figma

Responsive Design

Platforms:

Github Netlify

Vercel

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT TECHNICIAN

Chukchansi Gold Resort & Casino | 2022-Current

Responsible for the support of computer systems, network equipment, and selected software on the property. Support end users and guests effectively in a 24x7x365 environment with any equipment problems. Maintain proper security levels and access rights for software end users.

- Implemented new Visitor Management System to streamline, manage, and log visitations and deliveries.
- Assisted with and updated KBs, storage inventory, and Active Directory.

CAPSTONE PROJECT TEAM

Clever Programmer Bootcamp | 2021-2022

Built a winning capstone full-stack application using React.js, Firebase, Restful API, Moralis, HTML5, CCS3, JavaScript and Netlify along with four other talented developers. Within two weeks' time, we brainstormed, wireframed, and developed in separate Git branches to create Meta Betas: A mobile-optimized web3 music marketplace to discover top 50 songs or albums.

- Lead with the implementation of Metamask using Moralis.
- Created frontend and backend of the login and signup page using Firebase to store users and data with email or Google authentication.

OPERATIONS MANAGER

Savory Sandwiches Inc. | 2018-2021

Responsible for the production of food, sales, and deliveries. Kept supply inventory up to par levels to meet customer demand. Promoted team efficiency and productivity. Created daily production schedules. Organized weekly employee shifts.

- Troubleshooted errors and maintained new Direct Store Delivery system, accounting software and workstations/devices.
- Implemented and managed new Vendor Management Software keeping track of sales, inventory, and ticket requests.

RELEVANT WORK

MUSIC MARKETPLACE WEB APP

Meta Beats [<u>Live link</u>]

(React.js, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, API, Firebase, Moralis, Netlify)

A mobile-optimized, web3 music marketplace to discover top 50 songs or albums with Metamask integration and email or Google authentication.